RESUME



NARESH PATEL

B/8 ILA Co. Op. Hous. Soci. Ltd.

Thakkarbapa Nagar road

Bapunagar,

Ahmedabad-382350

M-9825927913

E-mail: foramnpatel@gmail.com

OBJECTIVES:

To build a good and prospective carrier in the field of Procurement and Purchase Department. To implement the complete knowledge and exposure, I had during my course of education and experience as well as to gain the best working exposure by serving an esteemed organization.

PERSONAL DATA:

Date of birth : 7-11-1972

Sex : Male - Married

Language known : English, Hindi & Gujarati

Last salary : Rs. 7.20 Lakh/year CTC

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION:

Diploma in Mechanical Engineering with1st class from Sir B.P.T.I. College Bhavnagar in 1992.

EXPERIENCE:

- Presently I am working with Vulcan Industrial Engineering Co. Ltd. Vitthal Udyoug Nagar as Manager Purchase since Aug. 2007
- From Jun. 1996 to May 2007 Ive worked with Texspin Bearings Itd. Ranpur. In Production, Maintenance and Purchase depts. as Sr. Engineer Prod. (Jun. 1996 to Dec. 1996), Sr. Engineer Maintenance (Jan. 1997 to Dec. 1999) and Manager Purchase (Jan. 2000 to May 2007).
- From Jun. 1995 to May 1996 I have worked with Nova International Ltd. Changodar as Asst. Production Engineer
- From Dec. 1992 to May 1995 I have worked with The Antifriction Bearings Corp. Ltd., Bharuch as Jr. Engineer (Production Grinding Shop).

Page: 01 of 02

COMPANY PROFILE:

- Vulcan Industrial Engineering Co. Ltd., an ISO 9001 certified company, is an engineering company engaged in manufacture of Blast Hole Drill Machine, Drill Rods, Mining Gearbox, Industrial Gearbox, and spares for Heavy Earth Moving Machines like Dragline, Shovel, etc.
- Texspin Bearings Limited, a TS 16949 certified company, is a precision engineering industries manufacturing Automotive and special purpose bearings and automotive parts. Product range covers steering Bearing, angular contact bearing, taper roller bearing, cylindrical roller bearing, Thrust Ball & Roller bearing and Automotive parts like Bush, detent pin Etc.The Company is supplies products to customers like Telco, Mahindra & Mahindra, Ashok Leyland, Escorts, Bajaj Auto, Bajaj Tempo Ltd, Sona steering, Rane, Eicher.etc
- Nova International Limited is a professionally managed precision engineering Industry manufacturing antifriction bearing covering product range single and Double row spherical Roller Bearing. Cylindrical Roller Bearing and U.C. Series Ball Bearing
- The Antifriction Bearings Limited, is a professionally managed precision engineering industry manufacturing antifriction bearings having machinery imported from world

renewed manufacturers such as IZK Japan and BWF Germany. Product range covers single Row Deep Groove Ball Bearing. Taper Roller Bearing. Cylindrical Roller Bearing and Thrust Bearing. Company supplies product to customers like Telco, Mahindra & Mahindra, Bajaj, Eicher, Ashok Leyland, Escort, Toyota, Kirloskar, etc.

PRESENT JOB PROFILE:

- Responsible for managing purchase team and reporting to Director.
- Implementation of purchasing and contract management instruction, policies and procedures.
- Guiding the team for carrying out the purchase activities as per purchase cycle.
- Techno-Commercial evaluation of the offers received & Negotiation with Vendors.
- Co-ordination with store, inventory monitoring, inventory cycle, Physical checking etc.
- Review purchase order claims and contracts for conformance to company policy.
- Vendor management relation and development, appraisal as per ISO & TS norms, resolve vendor grievances, and claims against supplies.
- Bill/invoice checking, Co-ordination with the accounts, to ensure timely payment.
- Import management viz. sourcing, negotiation, PO, Performa Invoice, LC scheduling shipments with relation to requirement, clearance of shipment. Imports pertain to bearings, Steel Tube, High tensile Plate, hydraulic parts, Capital goods
- Co-ordination, negotiation with CHA forwarder, shipping lines, end-to-end follow up for the shipments, etc.
- Procurement of raw material like round bar, forgings, castings, Steel Plate, CRCA sheet,
 Rubber Parts consumable goods, Hydraulic Electrical, Item parts etc.
- Cost benefits through competition amongst Vendor.
- Exposure to ERP environment, ISO 9000, QS 9000 & Ts 16949 Quality System standard.

NARESH PATEL Page: 02 of 02